Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of New York University COVID-19 Webpages MC.353
New York University Archives
New York University Archives Collection of New York University COVID-19 Webpages
March 2020-ongoing
New York University Archives
New York University
New York University in Abu Dhabi
New York University in Shanghai
MC.353
229 websites
This collection contains websites regarding New York University's response to the COVID-19 pandemic, starting in March 2020. It includes webpages from the University's campuses worldwide that represent advocacy, information, policies, protest, research, and scholarship created by individuals and communities within NYU, including administrators, faculty, students, staff, alumni, and prospective students at the New York campus, study away sites, and the campuses in Shanghai and Abu Dhabi.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Conditions Governing Access
Material pertaining to individual student records may be restricted in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). Please contact the Archives with specific questions regarding access to such records.
Arrangement
Websites are arranged alphabetically.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Websites are selected by University Archivist Janet Bunde and web archivist Nicole Greenhouse through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. The accession numbers associated with these websites are 2020.025, 2020.027, 2020.029, 2020.030, 2020.032, 2020.033, 2020.036, 2020.037, 2020.038, 2021.002, 2021.009, 2021.012, 2021.014, 2021.016, 2021.017, 2021.019, 2021.041, 2021.042, 2021.043, 2021.045, 2021.046, 2021.047, 2021.051, 2021.054, 2021.057, 2021.060, 2021.061, 2021.063, 2021.064, 2022.005, 2022.007, 2022.008, 2022.010, 2022.024, 2022.057, 2022.072, 2022.084.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
Historical Note
In March 2020, non-essential businesses throughout New York City closed in an effort to contain COVID-19, a respiratory virus that was first identified in December 2019. These closures included New York University (NYU) buildings. On March 11, 2020, classes were directed to teach remotely and non-essential employees were directed to work from home. These closures not only affected by the New York campus, but global study away sites and the campuses in Abu Dhabi and Shanghai. In July 2020, the university began planning for a hybrid work and learning. For the Fall 2020 semester, NYU implemented a coronavirus testing program as well as guidance for students related to masking, dorms, cleaning, shared spaces, classrooms, and quarantine and isolation procedures. For staff and faculty, guidance included events, research and laboratories, health information, travel policies, teaching, and research and laboratory procedures. In early 2021, the COVID-19 vaccine became available and NYU held a vaccine clinic toward the end of the Spring 2021 semester. NYU required vaccination for the 2021-2022 academic year. By the Fall 2021 semester, majority of remote learning ended, but with flexibility for students who tested positived for the coronavirus. Throughout the 2021-2022 academic year, the university dealt with both the Delta and Omicron variant surges. As of this writing (June 2022), the NYU still has protocols regarding the virus.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains websites regarding New York University's response to the COVID-19 pandemic. It includes webpages from the University's campuses worldwide that represent advocacy, information, policies, protest, research, and scholarship created by individuals and communities within NYU, including administrators, faculty, students, staff, alumni, and prospective students at the New York campus, study away sites, and the campuses in Shanghai and Abu Dhabi. It reflects decisions made by the University to close its campuses and buildings and to change or cancel the regular operation of the University, including in-person events, instruction, and research, as well as how these decisions were communicated to communities within the University; how communities at the University confronted telework and remote instruction; initiatives across the University to conduct research, publish articles, or otherwise fight the spread of the pandemic or analyze its effects; initiatives to aid students and staff within the community during the crisis; and research and thought around the pandemic with a particular focus on the social sciences.
As the pandemic continued, websites included information on reopening the campus with health and safety guidance regarding testing, masking, vaccines, social distancing. The website also tracked the spread of infection on campus. As the pandemic continued, the website also contained information related to the Delta and Omicron variant surges.
Related Materials
New York City COVID-19 Web Activism Collection (TAM 798) New York City Arts Community COVID-19 Response Web Collection (MSS 603)
COVID-19 (Disease); Universities and Colleges -- Administration; Public health -- United States.; Education, Higher.; Hamilton, Andrew D. (Andrew David)
- A Message From NYU President Andy Hamilton, March 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
  Scope and Contents
  Video of President Andy Hamilton addressing the NYU community in light of the changes to University life brought by COVID-19.
- Academics and Research Guidelines, July 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Accommodations and Modifications, July 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Acts of Kindness Quarantine Cookbook, March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
  This page describes the creation of the Quarantine Cookbook, which compiled recipes from residents in faculty housing.
- Affiliates, September 2021-March 2023 (Box Electronic Records)
- AMC COVID-19 Forum Resources, May 2020-March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Arriving to Campus, July 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Athletics, Recreation, and Fitness, August 2020-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Back to Campus Gallery, September 2020-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Binx Test Kits, September 2021-September 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Binx Test Kits, August 2022-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- BioReference Testing Site, September 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Building Access, August 2020-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Building Basics, July 2020-July 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Building HVAC Systems, July 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Campus Activities and Spaces, March 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- Campus Activities and Spaces, March-August 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- Campus Life, July 2020-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Campus Visitors, July 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- Checking In and Out of Housing, July 2021-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- Classes and Academics, March 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- Classes and Academics, March-September 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- Classroom Technology and Audio Visual Equipment Cleaning Guidelines, August 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Classrooms and Classes, July 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Classrooms and Classes, July 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Coming to New York City from Elsewhere, July 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Commuter Buddy Program, August 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Commuting, July 2020-July 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Compliance with Safety and Health Rules, August 2020-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Connecting NYU Alumni Around the World Digitally During COVID-19, April 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- Contact Tracing, July 2020-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Conversemos COVID-19 (Let's Talk COVID-19), August 2020-March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
  This page includes videos promoting mask wearing recorded in various indigenous languages, including Quechua, Haitian Kreyòl, Nahuatl, Mixteco, Garifuna, and Kichwa.
- Coronavirus Testing, Prevention, and Quarantine, July 2020-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Coronavirus updates from NYU, July 2020-June 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Coronavirus-Related Benefits Updates, March 2020-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID-19 Agency Announcements, March 2020-May 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID-19 Coronavirus: NYU Dentistry Info and Resources, July 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID-19 Health Alert & FAQ, March-August 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID-19 Information for Admitted Students, March 2020-October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID-19 Pandemic Perspectives, April 2020-June 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID-19 Related Announcements, May 2021-October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID-19 Related Events, October 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Covid-19 Teaching Resources (NYUAD), December 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID-19 Testing, August 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID-19 Testing and Vaccination Data, September 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID-19 Transportation Updates, September 2020-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID-19 Updates for the NYU Shanghai Community, March 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID-19 Vaccine, January 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
  This page describes the availability of vaccines to the NYU community and suggests ways that the community can remain safe throughout the vaccination process.
- COVID-19 Vaccine and Boosters, August 2022-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID-19: NYU in the News, April 2020-October 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
  Website related to the NYU COVID-19 response containing links to articles on how NYU community members have responded to the pandemic.
- COVID-19: NYU in the News, April 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID-Related Support, July 2020-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
  This page describes resources and support offered to students, parents of students, and employees of the University.
- COVID-Related Guidance, August 2022-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID19 and Its Afterlives, November 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- COVID19 and Its Afterlives Videos, April-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Daily COVID-19 Screener for Campus Access, July 2020-September 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Day of Your Appointment, April 2021-July 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Department of Comparative Literature COVID-19 Dashboard, March-November 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
  This page describes information collated and shared by administrators in the Department of Comparative Literature in the Faculty of Arts and Science at NYU.
- Dining, July 2020-July 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Eating and Drinking on Campus, August 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Employee Return to Campus Testing and Quarantining, August 2020-January 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Enhanced Building Cleaning and Disinfection, July 2020-July 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Enhanced Building Cleaning and Disinfection, August-September 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- Exemptions Process, September 2021-March 2023 (Box Electronic Records)
- Faculty Return to Campus Testing and Quarantining, August 2020-January 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- FAS Office of Educational Technology (Arts and Science), February-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- General FAQs and Support, March 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- General FAQs and Support, March-August 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- Get Involved: NYC COVID-19 Relief, April 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
  Website related to the NYU COVID-19 response on how NYU community members can get directly involved in New York City COVID-19 relief efforts.
- Getting Courses Ready for Fall (Wagner), February 2021-January 2023 (Box Electronic Records)
- Graduate Admissions COVID-19 FAQs, April-September 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- GSAS Coronavirus Information, July 2020-March 2023 (Box Electronic Records)
- GSAS COVID-19 Resources, July 2020-October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Health Alerts, March 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- Historians Respond to Covid 19, June 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- In-person Events, July 2020-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Information for Researchers, July 2020-March 2023 (Box Electronic Records)
- Instructional Planning Site (Liberal Studies), February-June 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Isolating or Quarantining in Student Housing, August 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Isolating or Quarantining in Student Housing, September 2020-May 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Isolating or Quarantining Off-Campus, August 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Isolating or Quarantining Off-Campus, December 2020-May 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Keep Each Other Safe: Everyday Basics, July 2020-March 2023 (Box Electronic Records)
- Kitchens, Pantries, and Break Rooms, July 2020-September 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Large Gatherings, September 2020-August 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Laundry Rooms, July 2020-July 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Libraries, July 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Libraries, July 2020-September 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Masks, August 2022-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- Medical Questions, April 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Meetings, July 2020-July 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Messages from Dean Trevor Morrison, July 2020-January 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Messages from Dean Trevor Morrison, December 2020-October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Messages to the Community, March 2020-July 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Messages to the Community: Recent Coronavirus Communications, March 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- Modifications to Safety and Health Rules, March-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYC COVID-19 Testing Data, September 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Abu Dhabi Coronavirus News, May 2020-October 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Abu Dhabi COVID-19 Latest News, August 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Abu Dhabi COVID-19 News, May 2020-October 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Abu Dhabi Official Updates, August 2020-October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Abu Dhabi Return to Campus, August 2020-April 2023 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Alumni Event Planning and Corona Disease, June 2020-March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
  This page is a letter addressed to alumni sharing COVID-related updates from the University.
- NYU Chemistry responds to COVID19, May 2020-March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
  This page details how NYU Chemistry community members have contributed toward scientific research and community building during the pandemic.
- NYU Coronavirus Information and Resources, March 2020-September 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Coronavirus Information and Resources, March 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Coronavirus Information for Employees, March 2020-March 2023 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Coronavirus Information for Faculty, March 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Coronavirus Information for Students, March 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU COVID-19 Emergency Relief Grant, March 2020-October 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU COVID-19 Task Force, April 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Dentistry COVID-19 Frequently Asked Questions, July 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Dentistry Health and Safety Plan/Guidelines, December 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Langone Health News Hub, March-August 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Langone Health News Hub Coronavirus Search Results, March 2020-October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Langone NewsHub on COVID-19, May 2020-October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
  News from NYU Langone regarding research and developments related to COVID-19.
- NYU Law COVID-19 Updates and Information, July 2020-October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Law COVID-19 Updates and Information, July 2020-January 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Law Remote and Hybrid Instruction Support Guide, November 2020-October 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Libraries Research Guide: Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19), April 2020-October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Mobilizes Against COVID-19, July 2020-June 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Reopening and Operating Plan for COVID-19, August-September 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
  This page includes a link to a copy of the reopening plan that New York University filed with the State of New York prior to offering in-person classes.
- NYU Responds to COVID-19, March 2020-September 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Returns, August 2020-October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
  Website containing updates on NYU Libraries services during the COVID-19 pandemic.
- NYU Returns Adjunct Faculty Video, September 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Returns Full-time Faculty Video, September 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Returns Webinar Series, August 2020-April 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Returns Webinar Series, July 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Returns: FAQ for Neighbors, March 2021-October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU School of Global Public Health COVID-19 - Student Remote Guide & Resources, July 2020-September 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Shanghai Digital Teaching Toolkit, March 2020-October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Shanghai News & Announcements, March 2020-April 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Steinhardt Coronavirus (COVID-19) Information, July 2020-October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Student Emergency Fund, November 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Tandon AirMOD and AirVENT, April 2020-March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Tandon responds to COVID-19, April 2020-October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
  This site describes projects undertaken by members of the NYU Tandon community to respond to COVID-19
- NYU Tandon Returns, June 2021-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Vaccine Clinic, April 2021-January 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYU Wagner Coronavirus Information, July 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- NYUAD COVID-19 Research, April 2020-October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- NYUAD Response to COVID-19, March 2020-April 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Office of Educational Technology (Dentistry), February-June 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Offices, July 2021-January 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Offices, July 2020-November 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- On the Frontline, March 2020-March 2023 (Box Electronic Records)
- Ongoing Testing, September 2020-September 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Online Learning (Silver), February-June 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Parents and Family, March 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Past NYU Alumni Virtual Events, July 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Personal Workspace Cleaning, July 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Physical Distancing, July 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Planning for Fall 2021 Study Away, March 2021-May 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Post-Vaccine Questions, April-August 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Proof of Vaccination, May 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Protective Equipment (PPE), July 2020-September 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Public Health Ambassadors, September 2020-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Quarantine and Isolation, August 2020-August 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Quarantine Dining Information, August 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- Remote Instruction (Tandon), August 2020-October 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Remote Instruction Toolkit (Nursing), February-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Remote Instruction Toolkit (SPS), February-June 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Remote Teaching (Stern), February-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Remote Work, July 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Research, July 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Research and Laboratories, March 2020-March 2023 (Box Electronic Records)
- Research and Laboratories, March 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- Research Reconstitution Plan FAQs, June-July 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- Residential Life & Housing Services Quarantine Information, January-May 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Residential Life Handbook, July 2022-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- Resources for Remote Teaching (Tisch), February-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Return to Campus Testing and Quarantining, July 2020-July 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Safety and Health, July 2020-March 2023 (Box Electronic Records)
- Scan and Reserve a Space, July 2021-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- Scheduling Your Vaccine, April 2021-January 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
- School of Global Public Health News, April-August 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- Self-Care for Challenging Times, March 2020-September 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Silver School of Social Work Updates on 2020-21, January-June 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Sponsors, September 2021-March 2023 (Box Electronic Records)
- SPS COVID-19 Updates, July 2020-March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
- Status of Operations, August 2020-August 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
  This page includes information about NYU's campuses and sites around the world, and what the status of each campus and site is for the Fall 2020 semester.
- Status of Operations, March 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- Status of Operations, March-July 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
- Staying Connected, March 2021-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)